[
  {
    "question": "Despite the smile that spread from ear to ear, her eyes relayed a certain _____.",
    "correct_answer": "sorrow",
    "distractor": [
      "jubilance",
      "mischievousness",
      "vision",
      "liveliness"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some historians see the Jacksonians as little more than ruthless capitalists who had _____ regard for individual welfare.",
    "correct_answer": "scant",
    "distractor": [
      "mixed",
      "undue",
      "inconsistent",
      "obtrusive"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/5ekxgk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of social science`s major themes is that of stability versus change; to what extent are individual personalities _____ yet different over time?",
    "correct_answer": "static",
    "distractor": [
      "transient",
      "maladj usted",
      "disturbed",
      "discreet"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/a9kxhk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Erie Canal`s completion caused _____ economic ripples; property values and industrial output along its route rose exponentially.",
    "correct_answer": "prodigious",
    "distractor": [
      "persist cut",
      "invaluable",
      "incredulous",
      "severe"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/55kxik/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Voters have become so inured to the fickle nature of politicians that they responded to the levy of a new tax with _____.",
    "correct_answer": "stolidity",
    "distractor": [
      "amazement",
      "exasperation",
      "alarm",
      "perplexity"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/48kxjk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The division between child-rearing goals that emphasize originality and personalization and those that place emphasis on adoption of conventions and compliance with rules discloses a _____that stems from the principles on which these goals are based.",
    "correct_answer": "contradiction",
    "distractor": [
      "monotony",
      "benefit",
      "forseeability",
      "genius"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/d0kxkk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite her mentor`s advice that she attempt to sound consistently _____, the graduate student often resorted to using slang when presenting significant parts of her thesis, her habitual speech patterns overriding her years of learning.",
    "correct_answer": "erudite",
    "distractor": [
      "lucid",
      "didactic",
      "panegyrical",
      "rational"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/9fl06k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Western culture has so influenced Middle Eastern music that even the latter`s roles of composer and performer, at one time inseparable, have now begun to _____.",
    "correct_answer": "diverge",
    "distractor": [
      "divulge",
      "retreat",
      "retrench",
      "fuse"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/cfl0xk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although tranquilizers usually have a _____effect, this is not always the case, especially when the abuse of these drugs results in a failure to induce the much-desired sleep.",
    "correct_answer": "soporific",
    "distractor": [
      "sedulous",
      "coruscating",
      "debilitating",
      "pond rat ing"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/46l0zk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Science and religion each have core tenets that are considered _____; however, because some scientific tenets are in conflict with some religious ones, these tenets cannot all be correct.",
    "correct_answer": "axiomatic",
    "distractor": [
      "historic",
      "disputable",
      "ubiquitous",
      "empirical"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/dfl19k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Oscar Wilde`s The Importance of Being Earnest satirizes the _____nature of upper crust British society; its characters take trivial concerns seriously while glibly dismissing important ones.",
    "correct_answer": "shallow",
    "distractor": [
      "maladaptive",
      "insincere",
      "unusual",
      "insignificant"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/77l1ck/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite what _____philosophies of child-rearing suggest, there is no imperative that the day-to-day action of raising a child be simple, unambiguous and unchanging-no requirement, in other words, ensures that life follow philosophy.",
    "correct_answer": "systematic",
    "distractor": [
      "inexact",
      "aggressive",
      "random",
      "shameless"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/bdl1zk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Having squandered his life`s savings on unprofitable business ventures, the _____entrepreneur was forced to live in squalor.",
    "correct_answer": "insolvent",
    "distractor": [
      "former",
      "unlikely",
      "perturbed",
      "eccentric"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/8bl23k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Video game enthusiasts know that, while the astounding advances in technological innovation might increase the level of fun of the gaming experience, such a result is by no means _____.",
    "correct_answer": "ineluctable",
    "distractor": [
      "desultory",
      "endemic",
      "salient",
      "seminal"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dismissed by the establishment, professing nothing but disdain for the canon, and yet beloved by his followers who trumpet his _____ opinions, the raffish pundit is laughing all the way to the bank.",
    "correct_answer": "iconoclastic",
    "distractor": [
      "blithe",
      "inveterate",
      "meretricious",
      "meritless"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/3ck3ik/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although his latest project was relatively _____-little more than a few basic plot points scribbled on a napkin-the veteran screenwriter easily sold the story to a major Hollywood studio.",
    "correct_answer": "undeveloped",
    "distractor": [
      "polished",
      "convoluted",
      "prosaic",
      "tortuous"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/3bk3mk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite being located in hot and sunny California, San Francisco is famous for its _____ weather, engendered by the confluence of two different meteorological systems in the Bay Area.",
    "correct_answer": "adverse",
    "distractor": [
      "stimulating",
      "balmy",
      "appealing",
      "duplicitous"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/e4k3nk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Possessing few natural resources upon its newly-granted independence in 1863, Singapore remained economically _____ until an influx of industrialization and foreign investment took hold there.",
    "correct_answer": "dubious",
    "distractor": [
      "powerful",
      "prosperous",
      "solvent",
      "fortuitous"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/31k3ok/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Even though legislators claimed the Contagious Diseases Acts strengthened the nation, social purists argued the Acts _____ the nation's moral growth by encouraging licentious behavior.",
    "correct_answer": "hampered",
    "distractor": [
      "advanced",
      "ameliorated",
      "supplanted",
      "enhanced"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/f2k3qk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The new lecture hall's _____ design reflected the architect`s minimalist influences.",
    "correct_answer": "unadorned",
    "distractor": [
      "posh",
      "intricate",
      "refulgent",
      "grandiose"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/91k3rk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern tennis fans have come to realize that, although, quantum technological leaps in racquet technology have lead to _____ increases in the speed and power with which players can hit the ball, this has not necessarily lead to a more entertaining game.",
    "correct_answer": "commensurate",
    "distractor": [
      "innocuous",
      "halcyon",
      "malleable",
      "tractable"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/9fk3uk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many Major League Baseball relief pitchers choose an electrifying theme song to play as they take the mound; the song _____ their fans and instills fear in their opponents.",
    "correct_answer": "innervates",
    "distractor": [
      "eviscerates",
      "enervates",
      "assuages",
      "pervades"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/8ak3vk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Emmet Ray, a fictional jazz guitarist in Woody Allen's film Sweet and Lowdown, is a paradoxical character; while he displays sophisticated musical artistry, his personality is typically _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "maladroit",
    "distractor": [
      "petulant",
      "elegant",
      "audacious",
      "multi-faceted"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/6fk3wk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Susan _____ the theater; she bought tickets for all the shows put on by the local drama group.",
    "correct_answer": "cherished",
    "distractor": [
      "abhorred",
      "owned",
      "loathed",
      "managed"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Currently _____ in philately, Roger decided to pursue his new hobby because he had already become an expert numismatist.",
    "correct_answer": "a dilettante",
    "distractor": [
      "a philanderer",
      "a mentor",
      "a specialist",
      "an eccentric"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/92k2fk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prior to taking on the new invader, the defending army had engaged in arduous combat; it is likely that the _____ resulting from waging two battles in two days played a part in its subsequent defeat.",
    "correct_answer": "enervation",
    "distractor": [
      "bellicosity",
      "pugnacity",
      "pacification",
      "aggravation"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/a6k2hk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ironically, the myth of Martin Van Buren`s _____ was due largely to circumstances that had little to do with Van Buren himself; in reality, of all the U.S. presidents since Andrew Jackson, Van Buren exceeded the average in education, intellect, and experience.",
    "correct_answer": "mediocrity",
    "distractor": [
      "profundity",
      "stoicism",
      "aptitude",
      "malleability"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f8k2kk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "While she may have answered him truthfully-in the strictest sense of the word-it became clear to Sergei after the incident that Sheryl had actually been trying to _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "obfuscate",
    "distractor": [
      "vituperate",
      "illuminate",
      "covet",
      "desiccate"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/5ck2mk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Certainly a roundabout narrative, the book-much like the others in the author`s pseudo-autobiographical series-proved to be unpopular among those who preferred _____ to loquaciousness.",
    "correct_answer": "succinctness",
    "distractor": [
      "enlargement",
      "garrulousness",
      "gregariousness",
      "perspicacity"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/69k2nk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although they stood with the congressman in a tenuous display of solidarity, the incensed commissioners could not conceal their _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "rancor",
    "distractor": [
      "camaraderie",
      "adulation",
      "facetiousness",
      "hubris"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f0k2pk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The defense attorney`s _____ closing statement was not enough to sway the jurors in his client`s favor; stirring words could not conceal the defendant`s evident guilt.",
    "correct_answer": "eloquent",
    "distractor": [
      "deceptive",
      "lengthy",
      "crafty",
      "impromptu"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/eek2tk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1770s colonial New England, Puritans _____ the celebration of Christmas, which they considered to be an odious reminder of the Pope`s tyranny.",
    "correct_answer": "repudiated",
    "distractor": [
      "placated",
      "extolled",
      "circumscribed",
      "tempered"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/cbk2vk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many dog owners treat their pets too _____ , forgetting that canines have evolved in competitive environments in which emotional coddling was a sign of weakness.",
    "correct_answer": "indulgently",
    "distractor": [
      "aggressively",
      "quixotically",
      "fortuitously",
      "belligerently"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/0ck2xk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Repulsed by _____ employees, the executive informed his staff that he preferred constructive criticism to calculated flattery.",
    "correct_answer": "obsequious",
    "distractor": [
      "natty",
      "profligate",
      "rapacious",
      "sententious"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/28k2zk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Students may consider modernist works such as James Joyce`s Finnegan's Wake to be more _____ than Victorian prose: Victorian narratives are linear and predictable, while Joyce`s tortuous plots are fragmented and fickle, and they confound the reader.",
    "correct_answer": "recondite",
    "distractor": [
      "banal",
      "elegiac",
      "mundane",
      "panegyric"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/26k30k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ancient generals, lacking modern technologies such as radio and satellite communication, often found that one of the most significant challenges in warfare was accurate _____ of the myriad of changes on the battlefield or in the campaign.",
    "correct_answer": "appraisal",
    "distractor": [
      "fortification",
      "adulteration",
      "accretion",
      "adumbration"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/2ek32k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "In psychological literature, the \"sleeper effect\" refers to the phenomenon in which a persuasive message from a trustworthy source loses _____ over time, while the efficacy of a message from a less credible source simultaneously increases.",
    "correct_answer": "cogency",
    "distractor": [
      "prescience",
      "erudition",
      "evasiveness",
      "control"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/9bk33k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pundits do not believe that the sporadic calls for her ouster-outcries spurred by both her unusual lifestyle and social policies-have compelled the monarch to seriously consider _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "abnegation",
    "distractor": [
      "vacillation",
      "castigation",
      "asceticism",
      "misanthropy"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f9k34k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dolly Madison., the wife of President James Madison., was known especially for her _____ , remaining calm even as the British invaded Washington D.C. during the War of 1812.",
    "correct_answer": "equanimity",
    "distractor": [
      "impracticality",
      "cynicism",
      "zeal",
      "malevolence"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/67k37k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Seth was extremely _____ , and did not enjoy activities that required effort to meet new people.",
    "correct_answer": "introverted",
    "distractor": [
      "extroverted",
      "gregarious",
      "lackluster",
      "jaded"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/70k38k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some religious leaders have declared inaction on environmental issues to be _____ , because it may now be considered a sin to pollute the earth.",
    "correct_answer": "iniquitous",
    "distractor": [
      "fathomable",
      "splenetic",
      "diaphanous",
      "dilatory"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/5ak3ak/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because he ate high-calorie snacks while riding the exercise bike, Julie ridiculed DeRay`s workout philosophy as _____.",
    "correct_answer": "fatuous",
    "distractor": [
      "pithy",
      "indolent",
      "hackneyed",
      "precarious"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f7k3bk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The recent convert, still a _____ with respect to the rites of her church, did not yet feel completely comfortable in her new faith.",
    "correct_answer": "tyro",
    "distractor": [
      "pilgrim",
      "iconoclast",
      "ascetic",
      "poseur"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/a4k3dk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Just as different people can have very different personalities, so too can pets-even those of the same species and breed possess varied _____.",
    "correct_answer": "temperaments",
    "distractor": [
      "initiations",
      "implementations",
      "aptitudes",
      "rationalizations"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "If one were asked who transmitted the first radio broadcast of the human voice, one might guess the _____ inventor Guglielmo Marconi, but in fact the feat was accomplished by the much less well-known Reginald Fessenden.",
    "correct_answer": "renowned",
    "distractor": [
      "infamous",
      "contingent",
      "cogent",
      "insistent"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/75k17k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Now known as Administrative Professionals` Day, Secretaries` Day was created in 1952 by Harry F. Klemfuss, a public relations professional who _____ the value and significance of administrative assistants in order to attract more women to the profession.",
    "correct_answer": "touted",
    "distractor": [
      "proscribed",
      "refuted",
      "undermined",
      "admonished"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/07k19k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "With a similar contrast between a partly cloudy sky and a dark street, the cover of the recent rock CD _____ a famous surrealist painting from the early 1900s.",
    "correct_answer": "evokes",
    "distractor": [
      "admires",
      "obfuscates",
      "disenchants",
      "sanctions"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/29k1bk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although John F. Kennedy was known for his carefree flag football games, Gerald Ford should be _____ as our football president: He turned down offers to play for two National Football League teams in order to pursue a career in public service.",
    "correct_answer": "apotheosized",
    "distractor": [
      "relegated",
      "abrogated",
      "annulled",
      "criticized"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/aak1ck/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Though many _____ endlessly praised his work, Dan often wished for some honest criticism.",
    "correct_answer": "sycophants",
    "distractor": [
      "pedants",
      "benefactors",
      "adversaries",
      "mavericks"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/0ek1dk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheila would often _____ about her boyfriend`s habits, but everyone could tell that her seemingly bitter complaints were mostly facetious.",
    "correct_answer": "rail",
    "distractor": [
      "waffle",
      "dissemble",
      "grieve",
      "mince"
    ],
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/b6k1hk/0/0/0/0/0"
  }
]
